# Liyou Zhang

San Francisco, CA · <u>liyou713@gmail.com</u> · 747 242 9039 · <u>github.com/liyouzhang</u> · Authorized to work in the U.S.

## **SUMMARY**

Data Scientist with three years of quantitative analytical experience in healthcare, logistics and financial industries. Recognized for fast learning ability and culture adaptability. Key qualifications:

- Machine Learning and Deep Learning with Python, Sklearn, Pandas, SQL, Spark, Hadoop, MongoDB, AWS
- Financial Modeling with advanced Excel in DCF modeling, M&A, Bloomberg; passed CFA level 1 exam

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Galvanize – Data Science Immersive**

San Francisco, CA

Partnered with Kiva for capstone project; received Google sponsorship for education

08/2018

- <u>Capstone Project</u>: partnered with Kiva.org to build lender archetypes with unsupervised machine learning algorithms
- Other projects: natural language processing (<u>topic modeling</u>), supervised machine learning (<u>user churn prediction</u>), regression (<u>price prediction</u> of heavy machinery), backend and database building (<u>fraud detection</u>)

#### **Roche / Genentech – Finance Perspectives**

Basel, Switzerland / San Francisco, CA

Global Leadership Development Program (1 of 3 selected from 1000+)

01/2017-03/2018

- Managed the P&L of two product alliances with annual profit sharing expense at \$1.2B; responsibilities included monthly closing, settlement payment, financial forecasting & budgeting, and business planning across multiple teams
- Supported management committees on financial aspects of disputes, litigation and strategic decision making
- Analyzed Medical Activities cost structure and set up benchmarks for future budget planning and transparency
- Improved overall team efficiency including reducing redundant questions 90% through designing and implementing a new platform as first-level support for financial queries from business units

## DP World - Investor Relations, M&A, Group Treasury Intern

Dubai, U.A.E.

Sponsored by Dubai Government (Dubai Business Associates Program, 1 of 40 selected from 4000+)

08/2015-08/2016

- Proactively identified 5 strategic acquisition assets through extensive M&A research covering 60 ports
- Delivered an industry ROCE benchmark presentation to the deputy CFO based on analysis of seven competitors
- Built a financial model and conducted an in-depth case study of a competitor to gain insights on South East Asia

## Caisse de dépôt et placement du Québec (CDPQ) - Research Intern

Beijing, China

2<sup>nd</sup> largest Canadian sovereign fund

09/2014-12/2014

- Monitored private equity market and complied daily reports for the HQ investment decisions
- Drafted China Mission brochure to introduce investment themes including Healthcare, Entertainment industries

#### **BNP Paribas – Fixed Income Sales Intern**

Beijing, China

8th largest bank by total assets

11/2013-01/2014

- Provided direct corporate clients support on FX hedging solutions, including daily pricing, generating term-sheets etc.
- Updated pitch books and scenario analysis worksheets; translated 10+ research reports to serve clients in China

## **EDUCATION & LEADERSHIP**

## Renmin University of China - Master of Finance

Beijing, China

GPA: 3.90/4, First Class Scholarship

Sciences Po – Exchange Program

Paris, France

Renmin University of China – Bachelor of Economics

Beijing, China

Honored Graduates of Beijing City (3%), Co-Founder of Lean In RUC

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: Native Mandarin speaker